Samee Chowdhury

416-997-9768 | s2chowdhury@torontomu.ca | Website

Hi,

My name is Samee Chowdhury, a full-time fourth year co-op student attending Toronto Metropolitan University under the computer science program. I have a passion for web, and mobile development.

In terms of my qualifications for the position, I have experience at 3 internships with a focus on web development. My first internship I developed MVP web apps for startup companies in the pursuit to gain funding using Vue.js and Firebase. Developing the web app Tenamint.we were successful in gaining the company funding. The second internship at GetQuorum dealt with a condo voting regulation platform where I took a fullstack role in developing their backend routes and updating the frontend UI with Node.js, SQL and AWS. Lastly, and most recently I worked at Publicis Sapient, a consulting company. I worked on a leading telecommunication company's solution and took the lead developing a web app that reduced call center traffic and offshored the load to the website. The tech stack consisted of Java spring boot for our REST api service, SQL, cloudrun and React.

Aside from work experience, I have participated in numerous hackathons and have recently achieved first place for a web app my team and I developed for Guelph's hackathon (**GryphHacks**) with the goal of reducing period poverty for women in Toronto. As of recently I have been working as a part time web developer for my University's newspaper team and am learning webGL as a side hobby to make games.

Additional details on my projects, and skills can be seen on my resume and github. For further information please feel free to reach out via email. I hope you consider my application and I look forward to speaking with you soon. Thank you for taking the time to provide this opportunity for me.

Sincerely, Samee Chowdhury

Samee Chowdhury

416-997-9768 | oceansam101@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/samee-chowdhury | github.com/oceansam

EDUCATION

Toronto Metropolitan University (Formerly Ryerson University)

Sep 2019 - May 2024

Computer Science CO-OP (B.Sc)

CGPA: 4.17/4.33

Experience

Software Developer Intern

May 2023 - Present

RBC

Toronto, ON

- Created the Polaris API for RBC One to provide dataset access to clients and internal departments, eliminating the need for manual email requests.
- Improved server-side pagination performance by implementing keyset pagination, resulting in reduced large offset queries and faster API response time.

Software Development Engineer Intern

Jun 2022 - Aug 2022

Publicis Sapient

Toronto, ON

- Integrated a chatbot using Typescript, React, and Java Spring Boot to automate and reduce live customer support inquiry loads by 30%.
- Developed a text intent detection microservice with Java Spring Boot to categorize end-user requests and provide suggested actions.
- Enhanced accessibility by adding text-to-speech workflow to provide support for users with visual impairment.

Software Engineer Intern

Sep 2021 - Jan 2022

GetQuorum

Remote

- Developed a user-friendly condo owner dashboard using Vue.js, Javascript, SQL and Express.js, facilitating data visualization of voting metrics.
- Added a self-service flow for users to update sensitive information, leveraging JWTs for authentication and bcrypt encryption for data protection.
- Implemented a relational entity that integrates role-based access control, SQL schemas, and CRUD endpoints for user management.

Frontend Engineer Intern

May 2021 - Aug 2021

Global Creative Technology

Waterloo, ON

- Collaborated with 3 engineers to build Tenamint, a digital card collection app using TypeScript, Vue.js and Firebase. Pitched the MVP to investors, securing \$60,000 in funding.
- Automated CI/CD pipeline for frontend UI and e2e testing using Cypress, Jest and Github actions.
- Implemented caching for large data queries to reduce redundant requests and optimize load times.

Projects

$\mathbf{Her}\ \mathbf{Needs}\ |\ \mathit{Vue.js},\ \mathit{Typescript},\ \mathit{Firebase},\ \mathit{Google}\ \mathit{Cloud}$

Github

- Led development in a full-stack web app with an interactive map to locate free menstrual products in public washrooms.
- Utilized the google maps api to dynamically generate markers based on geospatial data stored in firestore.
- Achieved 1st place overall at GryphHacks.

Smart Pot $\mid C++$, Flask, Typescript, Express, Vue

Github

- Built a plant metric tracker that transmits data from an Arduino using socket Io to a python server which updates the website and sends warnings on discord in real time.
- Achieved top 25 at RuHacks.

TMU Explorer | Typescript, Three.js, React, Blender - WIP

Demo

- Created a 3D replica of the Toronto Metropolitan University campus using blender, for new students to explore.
- Modeled buildings to scale and added camera animations to tween between building locations.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Typescript, Python, Java, SQL, C, HTML/CSS, C++

Frameworks: React, Node.js, Nest.js, Angular, Vue, Next.js, Java Springboot, Jest, React-Native/Expo Developer Tools: Git, Google cloud, Docker, MongoDB, Jenkins, AWS, Firebase, Unity, Unix/Linux

TORONTO METROPOLITAN UNIVERSITY

Undergraduate

Samee Chowdhury Name:

Student ID: 500965772 OEN: 439085739

Print Date: 01/01/2023 05/16/2001 Birthdate:

Academic Program History

Computer Science Active in Program Program:

07/20/2019: 07/20/2019:

Computer Science Active in Program

Program: 01/07/2021:

01/07/2021: COMPUTER SCIENCE CO-OPERATIVE PROGRAM

COMPUTER SCIENCE Major

Beginning of Undergraduate Record

Fall 2019

Session:Unde	rgraduate Re	egular					
Course		De	escription escription	<u>Attempted</u>	<u>Earned</u>	<u>Grade</u>	<u>Points</u>
CPS	109	Co	omputer Science I	1.000	1.000	В	3.000
CPS	213		omputer	1.000	1.000	A-	3.670
			rganization I				
MTH 110			screte	1.000	1.000	A-	3.670
D00			athematics I	4 000	4 000	0	0.000
PCS	110		nysics	1.000	1.000	С	2.000
PHL	214	Cr	itical Thinking I	1.000	1.000	B-	2.670
				<u>Attempted</u>	Earned	GPA Units	<u>Points</u>
Term GPA		3.000	Term Totals	5.000	5.000	5.000	15.010
Transfer Term GPA			Transfer Totals	0.000	0.000	0.000	0.000
Combined GPA		3.000	Comb Totals	5.000	5.000	5.000	15.010

Academic Standing Effective 12/19/2019: Academic Standing: Clear

Winter 2020

Session:Under Course	graduate Re		escription	Attempted	Earned	Grade	Points
CPS	209		omputer Science II	1,000	1.000	A+	4.330
CPS	310	Co	omputer ganization II	1.000	1.000	Ä	4.000
CPS	412		oc Issues, Ethics of Profess	1.000	1.000	A+	4.330
MTH	207		alc and Computatnlethods I	1.000	1.000	A+	4.330
MUS	201		ro to Classical usic	1.000	1.000	В	3.000
				Attempted	Earned	GPA Units	<u>Points</u>
Term GPA 4.		4.000	Term Totals	5.000	5.000	5.000	19.990
Transfer Term GPA			Transfer Totals	0.000	0.000	0.000	0.000
Combined GPA 4		4.000	Comb Totals	5.000	5.000	5.000	19.990

Term Honor: Dean's List

Academic Standing Effective 05/13/2020: Academic Standing: Clear

Fall 2020

Session:Undergraduate Regular												
	Course			escription	<u>Attempted</u>	<u>Earned</u>	<u>Grade</u>	<u>Points</u>				
	CMN	300		omm in the omputer Industry	1.000	1.000	Α	4.000				
	CPS	305		ata Structures	1.000	1.000	A+	4.330				
CPS 393			1U	troduction to C and NIX	1.000	1.000	A+	4.330				
	CPS	530	De	eb Systems evelopment	1.000	1.000	A+	4.330				
	MTH	108		near Algebra	1.000	1.000	A+	4.330				
	MTH	380		obability and atistics I	1.000	1.000	Α	4.000				
					Attempted	Earned	GPA Units	<u>Points</u>				
	Term GPA 4.2			Term Totals	6.000	6.000	6.000	25.320				
	Transfer Term GPA			Transfer Totals	0.000	0.000	0.000	0.000				
	Combined GPA 4.2			Comb Totals	6.000	6.000	6.000	25.320				
Academic Standing Effective 01/11/2021: Academic Standing: Clear												
Winter 2021												
Session:Undergraduate Regular												
Course				escription escription	<u>Attempted</u>	Earned	<u>Grade</u>	<u>Points</u>				
	CPS	406		tro to Software	1.000	1.000	Α	4.000				
	CPS	420		screte Structures	1.000	1.000	A+	4.330				
	CPS	506		omparative Prog anguages	1.000	1.000	A+	4.330				
	CPS	590		perating Systems I	1.000	1.000	Α	4.000				
	CPS	847		oftware Tools for artups	1.000	1.000	Α	4.000				
					Attempted	Earned	GPA Units	Points				
	Term GPA 4.		4.130	Term Totals	5.000	5.000	5.000	20.660				
	Transfer Term GP/	A		Transfer Totals	0.000	0.000	0.000	0.000				
Combined GPA 4.1			4.130	Comb Totals	5.000	5.000	5.000	20.660				

Term Honor: Dean's List

Academic Standing Effective 05/10/2021: Academic Standing: Clear

<u>Grade</u>

PSD

GPA Units

<u>Grade</u>

GPA Units

0.000

0.000

0.000

27.000

0.000

27.000

0.000

0.000

0.000

Points

0.000

Points

0.000

0.000

0.000

Points

0.000 0.000 0.000

0.000

Points

0.000

0.000

0.000

104.980

104.980

0.000

TORONTO METROPOLITAN UNIVERSITY

Undergraduate

Name: Samee Chowdhury

Student ID: 500965772 OEN: 439085739

Spring/Summer 2021									Spring/Sun	nmer 2022			
Session:Spring - Regular							Session:Undergraduate Regular						
Course	Description	Attempted	Earned	<u>Grade</u>	<u>Points</u>		Course		Description	Attempted	Earned		
CPCS 18	81 Introduction to Astronomy	1.000	1.000	Α	4.000		WKT 3	03	Work Term III Computer Science	0.000	0.000		
Session:Undergraduate Regular										Attempted	Earned	(
Course	<u>Description</u>	Attempted	Earned	<u>Grade</u>	<u>Points</u>		Term GPA	0	000 Term Totals	0.000	0.000	_	
WKT 10	03 Work Term I	0.000	0.000	PSD	0.000		Transfer Term GPA	0.	Transfer Totals	0.000	0.000		
		Attempted	Earned	GPA Units	<u>Points</u>		Combined GPA	0.	000 Comb Totals	0.000	0.000		
Term GPA	4.000 Term Totals	1.000	1.000	1.000	4.000								
Transfer Term GPA	Transfer Totals	0.000	0.000	0.000	0.000		Fall 202		2022				
Combined GPA 4.000 Comb Totals 1.000 1.000			1.000	4.000		Session:Undergraduate Regular							
Academic Standing E	ffective 08/24/2021: Academic Sta	anding: Clear					Course CPS 5	10	<u>Description</u> Database Systems I	Attempted 1.000	<u>Earned</u> 0.000		
							CPS 5	11	Computer Graphics	1.000	0.000		
	Fal	l 2021						33 21	Computer Security Artificial Intelligence I	1.000 1.000	0.000		
Session:Undergradua	ate Regular							93	The Geography of	1.000	0.000		
Course	<u>Description</u>	<u>Attempted</u>	Earned	<u>Grade</u>	<u>Points</u>			Toronto					
WKT 20	03 Work Term II	0.000	0.000	PSD	0.000					Attempted	Earned	(
		Attempted	Earned	GPA Units	<u>Points</u>		Term GPA	0.	000 Term Totals	5.000	0.000	7	
Term GPA	0.000 Term Totals	0.000	0.000	0.000	0.000		Transfer Term GPA		Transfer Totals	0.000	0.000		
Transfer Term GPA	Transfer Totals	0.000	0.000	0.000	0.000		Combined GPA	0.	000 Comb Totals	5.000	0.000		
Combined GPA	0.000 Comb Totals	0.000	0.000	0.000	0.000								
							Undergraduate Career Totals Cum GPA: 3.890 Cum Totals 32.000 27.000						
Winter 2022							Transfer Cum GPA	3.		0.000			
Session:Undergradua								0	Transfer Totals		0.000		
<u>Course</u>	Description	Attempted	Earned	Grade	Points 4.330		Combined Cum GPA	. 3.	390 Comb Totals	32.000	27.000		
	Alternative Energies Communication and	1.000 1.000	1.000 1.000	A+ A+	4.330 4.330		End of Undergraduate						
CPS 6	Social Media 16 Algorithms	1.000	1.000	Α	4.000								
CPS 70	06 Computer Networks I	1.000	1.000	A-	3.670								
CPS 8	70 Applied Natural Lang. Process.	1.000	1.000	Α-	3.670								
		Attempted	Earned	GPA Units	<u>Points</u>								
Term GPA	4.000 Term Totals	5.000	5.000	5.000	20.000								
Transfer Term GPA	Transfer Totals	0.000	0.000	0.000	0.000								
Combined GPA	4.000 Comb Totals	5.000	5.000	5.000	20.000								
Academic Standing Effective 05/04/2022: Academic Standing: Clear													